Walter Snow Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
- Series IV: Fictional Works, undated, 1928-1973
  - Subseries C: Poetry, undated, 1927-1972
    - The Glory and the Shame, corrected copies, 1971-1972 (Box 9:, Folder 211)
    - The Glory and the Shame, corrected copies, 1971-1972 (Box 9:, Folder 212)
    - Four poems possibly removed from The Glory and the Shame, circa 1971-1972 (Box 9:, Folder 213)
      - "Columbine, Colorado", 1927
      - "Priapus", written draft removed to Folder 186, 1944
      - "The Name Is Fascination", undated
      - "A Roman Priest of 410 A.D.", undated
    - Correspondence with Open Places (poetry magazine), 1971-1973 (Box 9:, Folder 214)
      - "The True Story of Madame Sosoctris", drafts and notes
    - Open Places, copies of magazine with Snow's publication, 1972 (Box 9:, Folder 215)
      - "The True Story of Madame Sosoctris", 1972 January
      - "The Nigger He Killed", 1972 May
    - "Spain: The Modern Phoenix" & "Elegy on the Dead of the International Brigades", 1972 (Box 9:, Folder 216)
    - Monday Writer's Group (Chaplin, CT), "The Failure, Dead at 44" and poems by others, 1972 (Box 9:, Folder 217)
    - "South of Hue" published in The Daily World, 1972 November 3 (Box 9:, Folder 218)
    - Poems in Progress, 1941-1942, 1960, 1971 (Box 9:, Folder 219)
      - "Mohawks in a Foreign City", 1941
      - "President Hayes-The Betrayer of 1877", 1942
      - "Brief Homage to Diana", 1960
      - "The Finest Hour of the State Troopers", 1971
      - "Another Premier Meets Justice", 1971
    - Poems Written Post-Hospitalization, circa 1971 (Box 9:, Folder 220)
      - "Involuntary Retirement"
      - "The Neglected Poet (from 1896 to 1916)"
      - "Ex-Romeo"
      - "Reflections in Rome's Protestant Cemetery"
      - "To Governor Rockefeller"
      - "Windham's Fourth Floor Nurses"
    - Poems in Progress, 1972-1973 (Box 9:, Folder 221)
      - Untitled poems/notes
      - "The Name is Fascination"
      - "Cellini"
      - "Those Ugly Words"
      - "A Pequot's Lamentation (1638)"
      - "The Failure, Dead at 44"
      - "The Haunted President"
      - "Dear Botticelli"
      - "Elaine"
      - "St. Helen Finds the True Cross"
      - "Spring-Time and Laura"
      - "Grandeur Remains"
- Series V: Short Fiction, undated, 1928-1933, 1941-1970
  - Subseries A: New York City Short Ficition, undated, 1928
    - "Dumas is Dead, Long Live Dumas", 1928 (Box 9:, Folder 222)
    - "Aunt Rashe's Hoard" (Box 9:, Folder 223)
    - "Great Granny" (Box 9, Folder 224)
    - "No Fingers" (Box 9:, Folder 225)
    - "Nocturne" (Box 9, Folder 226)
    - "The Three Thanes" (Box 9:, Folder 227)
    - "You can't get Sentimental" (Box 9, Folder 228)
  - Subseries B: Chaplin, CT Short Ficition, undated, 1930-1931
    - "On the Spot", 1930 (Box 9:, Folder 229)
    - "The Nemesis of Flash Dolan" (original version of "The Bumboat Blind"), 1930 (Box 9:, Folder 230)
    - "The Bumboat Blind", 1930 (Box 9:, Folder 231)
    - "Ticket to Hell", 1930 (Box 9:, Folder 232)
    - Notes on potential story "Bullets and Snails", 1930 (Box 9:, Folder 233)
    - "Bullets and Snails", 1930 (Box 9:, Folder 234)
    - "One--Way Ride", 1930 (Box 10:, Folder 235)
    - "The Greatest Northwood's Guide", 1931 (Box 10:, Folder 236)
    - "A Moll's Last Clean-up" (Box 10:, Folder 237)
    - "Adventures all Luck Amuck" (Box 10:, Folder 238)
    - "Chinese Death" (Box 10:, Folder 239)
    - Character outline for "Gambler's War" (Box 10:, Folder 240)
    - "Gambler's War" (Box 10:, Folder 241)
    - "Gambler's War" (Box 10:, Folder 242)
    - "Gold Star Reporter" (Box 10:, Folder 243)
    - "Kid Road Builder" (Box 10:, Folder 244)
    - "Pagoda Secret" (Box 10:, Folder 245)
    - "Star Witness" (Box 10:, Folder 246)
    - "The End of the Hunt" (Box 10:, Folder 247)
    - "The Jade of Mei Quong" (Box 10:, Folder 248)
    - "The Real McCoy" (Box 10:, Folder 249)
  - Subseries C: Willimantic, CT Short Ficition, undated, 1931-1932
    - "Blackmailer", 1931 (Box 10:, Folder 250)
    - Notes on potential story "The Goetz Kill: Candidate for the Hot Squat", 1931 (Box 10:, Folder 251)
    - "The Goetz Kill: Candidate for the Hot Squat", 1931 (Box 10:, Folder 252)
    - "The Heir of Boss Mahoney", 1931 (Box 10:, Folder 253)
    - Notes on potential story "The Third Killer", 1931 (Box 10:, Folder 254)
    - "A Note on 'The Third Killer' for The Story Tellers' Circle", 1931 (Box 10:, Folder 255)
    - "The Third Killer", 1931 (Box 10:, Folder 256)
    - "Headlines in Hell", 1932 (Box 10:, Folder 257)
    - "Burmese Revenge" (Box 11:, Folder 258)
    - "Daly's Reply" (Box 11:, Folder 259)
    - "Dragon's Charmer" (Box 11:, Folder 260)
    - "Hell's Murder Extra" (Box 11:, Folder 261)
    - "One Hour to Catch His Ship" (Box 11:, Folder 262)
    - "Racketeer's Justice" (Box 11:, Folder 263)
    - "Ryan's Reply" (Box 11:, Folder 264)
    - "Sicilian Banquet" (Box 11:, Folder 265)
    - "The Blizzard Killer" (Box 11:, Folder 266)
    - "The Devil's Age" (Box 11:, Folder 267)
    - "The Gloom-Chaser" (Box 11:, Folder 268)
    - "The Old Life" (Box 11:, Folder 269)
    - "The Phantom Terror" (Box 11:, Folder 270)
    - Notes on potential story "To be Called Suicide" (Box 11:, Folder 271)
    - "To be Called Suicide" (Box 11:, Folder 272)
  - Subseries D: Individual Works, 1941-1970
    - "Heat Wave", 1941 (Box 11:, Folder 273)
    - "Prospect Avenue", 1941 (Box 11:, Folder 274)
    - "The Former Lieutenant Governor", 1941 (Box 11:, Folder 275)
    - "Thunderbolt", 1941 (Box 11:, Folder 276)
    - "The Moving Finger", 1948 (Box 11:, Folder 277)
    - "A White Lily for Corpse", 1948-1949 (Box 11:, Folder 278)
    - "The Bleeding Hand", 1949 (Box 12:, Folder 279)
    - Correspondence about Mystery Story Writing (Mystery Writers of America, information about stories), circa 1949-1955 (Box 12:, Folder 280)
    - "What Would You Do?", 1951 (Box 12:, Folder 281)
    - "Whiplash", 1951 (Box 12:, Folder 282)
    - "Jacklighter", pages 1-94, 1952-1953 (Box 12:, Folder 283)
    - Annotated draft of "Jacklighter", 1952-1953 (Box 12:, Folder 284)
    - Annotated draft of "Jacklighter", 1952-1953 (Box 12:, Folder 285)
    - Annotated draft of "Jacklighter" with outline, 1952-1953 (Box 12:, Folder 286)
    - "Pushover", 1953 (Box 12:, Folder 287)
    - "Lonely Hearts", 1955 (Box 12:, Folder 288)
    - Drafts and notes for "My Stepson Tiger", 1955 (Box 12:, Folder 289)
    - Drafts and notes for "My Stepson Tiger", 1955 (Box 12:, Folder 290)
    - "Hitch", 1956 (Box 12:, Folder 291)
    - "I Killed a Kid Last Night", 1956 (Box 12:, Folder 292)
    - "I Wanted to be a Man for Her", 1956 (Box 12:, Folder 293)
    - "I, Too, Was Guilty", 1956 (Box 12:, Folder 294)
    - "Protector", 1956 (Box 13:, Folder 295)
    - "Trapped", 1956 (Box 13:, Folder 296)
    - "Unforgivable", 1956 (Box 13:, Folder 297)
    - "Visitor From Boston", 1956 (Box 13:, Folder 298)
    - "Cross Your Heart", 1956-1957 (Box 13:, Folder 299)
    - "Press Agent for Murder", 1958 (Box 13:, Folder 300)
    - "Nightmare Drive", 1960 (Box 13:, Folder 301)
    - "Darkling, I Listen", 1962 (Box 13:, Folder 302)
    - "The Dear, Little Thing", 1965-1966 (Box 13:, Folder 303)
    - "Another Circe", 1965-1967 (Box 13:, Folder 304)
    - "Release", 1966 (Box 13:, Folder 305)
    - "Ever See a Dream…Running" drafts (published in Topper magazine), 1966-1967 (Box 13:, Folder 306)
    - "Ever See a Dream…Running" drafts (published in Topper magazine), 1966-1967 (Box 13:, Folder 307)
    - "The New Neighbor", 1966-1967 (Box 13:, Folder 308)
    - "The One Night She Became Really Mellow", 1967 (Box 13:, Folder 309)
    - "Master of Education", 1968 (Box 13:, Folder 310::)
    - "Said the Spider", 1970 (Box 13:, Folder 311)
    - Published versions of stories in pulp fiction magazines (clippings) (Box 13:, Folder 312)
      - "Gangster Suicide", published in Gang World, 1931 May
      - "The Death Hunch", published in Short Stories, 1932 April 25
      - "Tickets to the Grave", published in Gang World, 1932 July
      - "The Moving Finger", published in 10-Story Detective Magazine, 1948 December
      - "No Stock in Graves", published in Dime Detective, 1950 January
      - "Boozer Take All", published in Black Mask, 1950 March 14
    - Published stories in various pulp fiction magazines (clippings) (Box 14:, Folder 313)
      - "Sky Scraper Blonde", published in 15-Story Detective, 1950 June
      - "Exclusive Sucker", published in Dime Detective, 1950 October
      - "The Guilty Innocent", published in 15-Story Detective, 1951 May
      - "Death -in the Bag", published in 15-Story Detective, 1950 April
      - "Dead Men Don't Shriek", published in Suspect, 1956 February
      - "The Late Mrs. Vogel", published in Suspect, 1956 August
      - "The Blizzard Killer", published in Detective
      - "White Lily of Doom", published in 10-Story Detective
  - Subseries E: Individual Works, undated
    - "A Hunch about Death" (Box 14:, Folder 314)
    - "Big News From Ireland" (Box 14:, Folder 315)
    - "Bowery Nocturne" (Box 14:, Folder 316)
    - "Death of the Assassin" (Box 14:, Folder 317)
    - "Hat Check Broad" (Box 14:, Folder 318)
    - "Long-Awaited Meeting" (Box 14:, Folder 319)
    - "Mr. Sheldon's Awakening" (Box 14:, Folder 320)
    - "Nice Guy Who Went Wrong" (Box 14:, Folder 321)
    - "Road Builder" (Box 14:, Folder 322)
    - "The Brief and Final Appearance of Mr. Hyde" (Box 14:, Folder 323)
    - "The Death Swindle" (Box 14:, Folder 324)
    - "The Husband Who Knew" (Box 14:, Folder 325)
    - "The Late Mrs. Vogel" (Box 14:, Folder 326)
    - "Theodosia--And Also Teddy" (Box 14:, Folder 327)
    - "They Can't Find Johnny" (Box 14:, Folder 328)
    - "Vengeance is the Lord's" (Box 14:, Folder 329)
- Series V: Notes, undated, 1926-1972
  - "Early Apprenticeship" (story notes prior to 1926) (Box 14:, Folder 330)
  - Analysis of thirteen issues of The Rebel Poet, circa 1932 (Box 14:, Folder 331)
  - Analysis of plays by Shaw, Odets, Chekhov, & O'Neill, circa 1934 (Box 14:, Folder 332)
  - Notes on Birth of a Nation, circa 1938 (Box 14:, Folder 333)
  - Notes for a novel Sisters, circa 1941-1945 (Box 14:, Folder 334)
  - Analysis of popular detective magazines, 1947 (Box 14:, Folder 335)
  - Notes and partial works, 1948-1952 (Box 14:, Folder 336)
  - "Introduction to Parables" lecture notes, 1958 (Box 14:, Folder 337)
  - Notes, circa 1959 (Box 14:, Folder 338)
  - Outline for story "The Man He Might Have Killed", 1960 (Box 14:, Folder 339)
  - Analysis of End of Night by John D. MacDonald, 1960 (Box 14:, Folder 340)
  - Notes and beginnings of Heretics and Tyrant Popes, 1962-1963 (Box 14:, Folder 341)
  - Beginning and outline of novel The Restless Years, 1963 (Box 14:, Folder 342)
  - Italian notes and review of Frank G. Slaughter's novel Constantine, 1965, 1969-1970 (Box 14:, Folder 343)
  - Notes for Willimantic Chronicle articles, 1967, 1970 (Box 14:, Folder 344)
  - Notes on O'Neil Plays, 1968 (Box 15:, Folder 345)
  - Notes on 1971 Coventry police scandal (Box 15:, Folder 346)
  - "Tri-towners" discussion group notes on novels discussed, 1971-1972 (Box 15:, Folder 347)
  - Analysis of the 1972 National Election (Box 15:, Folder 348)
  - Outline of American Voices, undated (Box 15:, Folder 349)
  - Analysis of stories, undated (Box 15:, Folder 350)
  - Notes on potential stories, undated (Box 15:, Folder 351)
  - Notes on potential novel Deep and Shallow Roots, undated (Box 15:, Folder 352)
  - Notes on potential novel Old Man Jesus, undated (Box 15:, Folder 353)
  - Analysis of Dashiel Hammett plots, undated (Box 15:, Folder 354)
  - Beginnings of stories, undated (Box 15:, Folder 355)
    - "All that Their Money Could Buy"
    - "Seven Unemployed"
- Series VI: Ephemera, undated, circa 1930-1973
  - Stories for The Anvil No. 10 (not written by Snow), 1933 (Box 15:, Folder 356)
  - Clipped reviews of Theatre Union plays (Negro Theatre), not written by Snow, 1934 (Box 15:, Folder 357)
  - Laurel Club Show script, 1961 (Box 15:, Folder 358)
  - Playbills and other print ephemera for plays, 1966-1971 (Box 15:, Folder 359)
  - Print ephemera related to 1968 O'Neill Theatre Foundation National Playwrights Conference (Box 15:, Folder 360)
  - Print ephemera related to Jack Conroy, 1971-1973 (Box 15:, Folder 361)
  - Clippings of poetry and book reviews, 1971-1972 (Box 15:, Folder 362)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated, circa 1930-1973 (Box 15:, Folder 363)
- Series VII: Pulp Literature, 1931-1968
  - 10 Story Detective Magazine
    - Vol. 16 No. 3, 1948 December
  - 15 Story Detective
    - Vol. 2 No. 4, 1950 April
    - Vol. 3 No. 1, 1950 June
    - 1951 May
  - Black Mask
    - Vol. 34 No. 2, 1950 March
  - Blue Steel Magazine
    - Vol. 1 No. 4, 1932 June
  - Complete Detective Novel Magazine
    - No. 54, 1932 December
  - Detective Action Stories
    - Vol. 3 No. 3, 1931 August
    - Vol. 5 No. 1, 1932 February
    - Vol. 5 No. 3, 1932 April
  - Dime Detective Magazine
    - Vol. 62 No. 1, 1950 January
    - Vol. 64 No. 2, 1950 October
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine
    - Vol. 19 No. 100, 1952 March
  - Excitement
    - Vol. 22 No. 2, 1931 April
  - Far East Adventure Stories
    - Vol. 4 No. 1, 1932 February
  - Gang World
    - Vol. 2 No. 1, 1931 February
    - Vol. 2 No. 4, 1931 May
    - Vol. 3 No. 1, 1931 June
    - Vol. 3 No. 2, 1931 July
    - Vol. 3 No. 3, 1931 August
    - Vol. 3 No. 4, 1931 September
    - Vol. 4 No. 1, 1931 October
    - Vol. 4 No. 2, 1931 November
    - Vol. 4 No. 3, 1931 December
    - Vol. 5 No. 1, 1932 February
    - Vol. 5 No. 2, 1932 March
    - Vol. 5 No. 3, 1932 April
    - Vol. 5 No. 4, 1932 May
    - Vol. 5 No. 2, 1932 July
    - Vol. 6 No. 3, 1932 September
    - Vol. 6 No. 4, 1932 October
  - Mike Shayne Mystery Magazine
    - Vol. 19 No. 4, 1966 September
    - Vol. 20 No. 2, 1967 January
    - Vol. 20 No. 4, 1967 March
  - Over the Top
    - Vol. 3 No.5, 1930 February
  - Popular Magazine
    - Vol. 103 No. 3, 1931 July
  - Rackateer Stories
    - Vol. 4 No. 4, 1931 September/October
  - Rackateer and Gangland Stories
    - Vol. 5/6 No. 1, 1932 June
  - Saint Detective Magazine
    - Vol. 9 No. 2, 1958 February
  - Short Stories
    - Vol. 134 No. 3, 1931 February 10
    - Vol. 135 No. 2, 1931 April 25
    - Vol. 138 No. 5, 1932 March 10
    - Vol. 138 No. 6, 1932 March 25
    - Vol. 139 No. 2, 1932 April 25
  - Suspect Detective Stories
    - Vol. 1 No. 1, 1955 November
    - Vol. 1 No. 2, 1956 February
    - Vol. 1 No. 3, 1956 June
    - Vol. 1 No. 4, 1956 August
  - Suspense Magazine
    - Vol. 1 No. 2, 1951 Summer
  - Trapped
    - Vol. 2 No. 2, 1957 August
  - Underworld Romances
    - Vol. 1 No. 1, 1931 November
  - 20 Great Tales of Murder, Helen McCloy and Brett Halliday, eds. London, England: Hammond, Hammond and Company, 1952.
  - Crooks' Tour, Bruno Fischer, ed. New York, NY: Dodd, Mead and Company, 1953.
  - Dangerous Dames, Make Shayne, ed. New York, NY: Dell Publishing Company, Inc., 1955.
  - Golden Nightmare by Walter Snow. New York, NY: Austin-Phelps, Inc., 1952.
  - Murder in Mond: An Anthology of Mystery Stories, Lawrence Treat, ed. New York, NY: E.P. Dutton and Company, Inc., 1967.
  - With Malice Toward All, Robert L. Fish, ed. New York, NY: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1968.
  - You Killed Slizabeth and other prize winning stories from 20 Great Tales of Murder by Brett Halliday. New York, NY: Hillman Books, 1960.